training.com 2008-09-24

# Privacy Policy

Privacy and Security Policy

Introduction  
Element K Corporation, on behalf of itself, and its affiliates and subsidiaries (“Element K”) is committed to upholding the highest security and privacy standards for our online products and services. Our Privacy and Security Policy has been developed as a core component of our commitment to combine the finest quality products and services with the highest level of integrity in dealing with our customers. This policy guides how we collect and use information about customers, and we commit that it will be continuously assessed against new technologies, business practices and standards being enacted by other internet-based companies.

Scope  
This Privacy and Security Policy guides how we collect and use information collected on the website where this Policy appears. This Policy does not extend to other online or offline sites, products, or services. Please read this Policy in its entirety. By using this website, you consent to the data practices described in this Policy.

Collection and Use of Information  
When you register to access our online learning service, purchase products or services through our website, request technical support for our products or services, or request information about our products and services, we collect applicable information from you. This information typically includes your name, mailing address, email address, telephone number, and, where applicable, usernames and passwords associated with our online learning service, and payment information for purchases. You may provide to us, at your option, other personal information from various locations within our service.  We use the information you submit to us to provide you with the service you request, which may include: access to our online learning service, billing and shipping of products or services you purchase from us, technical support, information about our products and services, or other communications.  If you access our online learning service through an employer-sponsored subscription, all information gathered through the online learning service may be revealed to your employer. This Policy does not apply to the use of your personal information by your employer.

We also collect certain information about your computer hardware and software, and your activity on our service. This information may include: your IP address, browser type, operating system, domain name, access times and referring Web site addresses. This information is used for the operation of our service, to maintain quality of our service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the site.

We use Cookies on our site for load balancing requests between web servers, as session identifiers, and to facilitate automatic login. Cookies are small data files that are transferred from a Web server to your browser. These files contain information that may later be read back by the Web server for identification purposes. Cookies provide you the ability to re-enter the site without logging in if you have chosen the auto login option. If you desire, most Internet browsers allow you to erase Cookies from your computer hard drive, block all Cookies or receive a warning before a Cookie is stored. 

We may disclose your personal information to any outside contractors, related companies and/or other companies that we use to ship products, provide technical support, handle order processing and/or otherwise act on our behalf for the purpose of providing products and services.  We also report data related to sales of third-party authorized courseware to applicable vendors according to applicable training certification standards. 

We may also disclose your personal information in the good faith belief that disclosure is necessary to resolve disputes, investigate problems, conform to the law, comply with legal process, protect and defend the rights, property, and safety of our company, its affiliates or partners, our and their respective employees and customers, or members of the public, or in connection with any sale of our company or any substantial portion of its assets.

Except as described in this Policy, we will not share any of your personal information with a third party without your permission.

Communications From Us  
Employer-Sponsored Students using our online learning service may receive event-triggered messages to facilitate use of the service, including, but not limited to, password reminders, registration confirmations and course/class start reminders.

  Employer-sponsored Administrators are provided access to various administrative functions used to manage a group of students. We communicate regularly to Administrators regarding service availability, service changes, learning effectiveness tools, user group events, and availability of new products. Additionally, Administrators may receive periodic newsletters describing best practices, industry news and various other topics we believe may be of interest to Administrators. Administrators use their own discretion as to whether or not to forward this information to their students.

We periodically communicate to users regarding service availability, service changes, and the availability of new products and services.  Additionally, users may receive periodic newsletters describing new product offerings and various other topics we believe may be of interest.  Users can opt-out of receiving e-mail promotions and information by editing their personal information.  Individuals who subscribe to e-mail newsletters are always offered the ability to opt-out of these services. 

Data Transfers   
Information we collect may be stored and/or processed in the United States or in any other country where we or our affiliates, subsidiaries, or agents maintain facilities. By using the site, you consent to the transfer of information outside of your country. We abide by the safe harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union.

Changing Your Personal Information   
We strive to keep your personal information accurate and up-to-date. Should you find inaccuracies in your personal information, please update your information using the available account maintenance functions on our service. All other account changes should be submitted in writing to Customer Service via our “Contact Us” function on the site.   
  
Chat Rooms and Threaded Message Boards  
We host chat rooms and facilitate threaded message board discussions in connection with many of our courses. Any information disclosed in these areas may be observed by other students and is not private or secure.

External Sites  
Our online learning service feature links to external websites, including those of our affiliates and third party partners. We recommend that you review the privacy policy of any external website that you may enter from our site. This includes, but is not limited to, the customer service assistance service operated by LivePerson, Inc., your use of which is subject to the privacy policy available at <http://www.liveperson.com/help/privacy.asp>. 

Security  
We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. For example, we store the personal information you provide on computer servers located in controlled facilities to which access is limited. Additionally, when we transmit sensitive data, such as your credit card number, over the Internet, we protect it through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

Notification of Changes  
We may make changes to this Policy at any time. If we make any changes to this Policy, we will post the changes on our site. You should check this Policy so you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under circumstances, if any, we disclose it. Your continued use of our service following any changes constitutes your agreement to this Policy, as changed.

Contact Information  
To contact us regarding this Policy, our practices, or your choices, you may contact us as follows:

Attn: Privacy Officer  
Element K   
500 Canal View Blvd.  
Rochester, NY 14623

e-mail:[ Privacy@elementk.com](mailto:Privacy@elementk.com)  
phone: 1-800-250-5013, and select option #4.

Effective as of: May 11, 2006
